Guide to the Youth Community Development Program records, 1972-2002
Youth Community Development Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Youth Community Development Program records 1972-2002
23-18-3654
Youth Community Development Program Dept. of Human Development
6.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Newspapers, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, studies, and various programs conducted within the College of Human Ecology and the ones in New York State are arranged by counties.
Includes videos of various symposiums, conferences and news reports.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
George Broadwell initiated the Youth Community Development Program in 1972, hiring Don Mac Vean to write a proposal to establish the effort in New York State. In 1973 Stephen Hamilton and Barbara Sagan were hired as extension associates to create the New York 4-H Community Development Program in the Dept. of Human Development. When they left in 1977, Herb Engman and Florence Cherry were hired and in 1980 Stephen Googin was hired. In 2004 the program, then called the Youth Community Action Program, was transferred to the New York State 4-H Office.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, studies, and various programs conducted within the College of Human Ecology and the ones in New York State are arranged by counties.
Includes videos of various symposiums, conferences and news reports.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Youth Community Development Program; Broadwell, George J.; Cherry, Florence.; Engman, Herbert J.; Googin, Stephen.; Hamilton, Stephen F.; Mac Vean, Donald.; Sagan, Barbara M.; Cornell University; New York 4-H Community Development Program.; New York State College of Human Ecology. Dept. of Human Development.; Youth Community Action Program.
Subjects:
Youth--United States--New York (State); Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Youth Programs, General
Box 1- Folders: 1- 33, Box 2- Folders: 1- 36, Box 3- Folders: 1- 36
Series II. New York State Youth Programs by County
Box 4- Folders: 1- 32, Box 5- Folders: 1- 36, Box 6- Folders: 1- 34
Series III. Videotapes
Box 8
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Youth Programs, General
  - Establishment of 4-H Development in New York State, 1965, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Establishment of 4-H Development in New York State, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Establishment of 4-H Development National, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New York State 4-H Community Development Guidelines for Grants, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 4-H Community Development- Program Brochures (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 4-H CRD Youth in Action Improving their Communities, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 4-H Community Development - Background Materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - New York State 4-H Community Development - Miscellaneous, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 4-H Community Development Progress Reports, 1973-1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 4-H Community Development Progress Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Youth Community Development Evaluation (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Youth Participation - A Concept Paper, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 4-H Enrollment Statistics, 1975-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Youth Court Material, 1970-1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Youth Court, 1975-2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Youth Employment, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Youth Employment, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Youth Employment, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Youth Employment Programs - Counties, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New York Youth Employment Program, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Migrant/4-H Camp Program Report, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - High School Interns in Local Government- Guide, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 4-H Club Community Development Projects - Guide, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Youth Action to Improve the Environment - Guide, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Leader Training Program Guide- 4-H Community Service (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Mayor's Youth Advisory Council - City of Oneida, New York, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Youth Involvement in Community Development Advisory Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Youth Survey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Heritage and Horizons, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - What Every Citizen Should Know- A Guide to Local Government, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - What Every Citizen Should Know (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - What Every Citizen Should Know- Student Handouts, Slide Scripts (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Opportunities for Young People in Tompkins County (New York State) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Adolescents- "Fact Sheet", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Playing for Real (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Let's Look into the Future (Madison, County, New York) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Freire Conference, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Local Government- 4th grade program- State Education Dept. Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Local Government- Regents- correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Local Government Intern Program- Resource Material, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - County and Local Government Internship Program Coordinator Meeting, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Local Government Intern Program - Teaching Activities (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Local Government Intern Program, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Local Government Intern Program- Questionnaires, talks, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Local Government Intern Program, 1983-1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Local Government Intern Program, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Local Government Intern Program, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Participation in Government Project, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program- Resource Material, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Local Government Program, 1983-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 4-H in Schools Task Force, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 4-H Community Development Position Paper, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Human Development and Family Studies Review (Extension), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Youth Volunteers Project - New York State 4-H and Kellogg Foundation, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Youth Volunteers Program - Table Charts (oversized) - After School Programs and 4-H Clubs and Community Improvement Projects, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Local Basis for 4-H Work, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Volunteers- Adolescents: Issues and Programs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Local Government Survey Programs, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 4-H Curriculum Team, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Experiential Learning, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Local Government List of Company Programs, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Making the Grade - New York State, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Making the Grade - New York State, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Youth at Risk, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Voting, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Training- Miscellaneous, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Public Policy- Tri-State Conference, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Local Government Internship Training (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Youth Development Training, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Youth and the Public Policy Process Training, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 4-H Recognition Task Force, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Project EASE (Exploring Aging through Shared Experiences), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - How to Access Youth Databases through CENET, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - National Youth Service Day, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Migrant Education Service - Learning Training, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Parent and Adolescent Communication, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Youth Community Service Guide, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Youth Community Service Training, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Youth Volunteering Survey, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Youth Community Action Evaluation (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - It's Your World, Make a Difference, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hunger- It's Your World, Make a Difference, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Beyond 4-H Community Service... To Community Service Learning, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NY 4-H Foundation Community Service Grants, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - National 4-H Council and Community Youth Development, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 4-H Review, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Linking Up" final report on a mentoring program for youth, 1990-06 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Establishment of the Teen Assessment Program (TAP) in New York State, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Establishment of the Teen Assessment Program (TAP) in New York State, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - TAP Implementation, 1992-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) College Grant, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) Manual (original), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) Innovations Award, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) Statewide Program Grant (not funded), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) Manual- New York State Adaptation, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wisconsin Youth Futures (Successor of TAP), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Teen Assessment Program (TAP) Broome County, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Team Assessment Project (TAP) Manual (original), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - TAP - Cayuga County, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - TAP - New York City, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - TAP - Tioga County, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - TAP - Allegheny County, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - TAP - Herkimer County, 1997-2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - TAP - Tompkins County, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - TAP - Oneida County, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - TAP - Town of Southampton (Suffolk County), 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Community Service in 4-H (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - School-to-Work and Youth Development: Identifying Common Ground Conference, 1995-04 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - How 4-H Contributes to Positive Youth Development, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Public Policies Education Training, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Public Policy Education- Alan Hahn Publications, 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Steve Hamilton Publications (Examples) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Public Policy Education Guides (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Youth Community Services- Continuum (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 4-H Youth Development Strategic Plan, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 4-H Capital Campaign, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Youth Community Action Program Work Team, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Program Support Requests from CCE Administration, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Youth Surveys and Youth Development Strategies: Lessons from the Field, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Work and Service, Employment and Citizenship: Convergent Competencies, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Youth Community Action Articles (Samples) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Youth Community Action Articles (Samples) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Youth in Local Government, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Youth Community Action- Human Development/Erie County/Tompkins County, 2003-2006 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Profiles of Youth Engagement and Voice in New York State - by Steve Goggin, Jane Powers and Sedra Spano, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Human Development and Family Studies- Steve Goggin's projects, 1984-1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Division for Youth- Latch Key Project, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Job Express- Steve Goggin, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - In depth Study Week- Public Policy for Youth, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "4-H Community Development in New York State"- Report by Herb Engman, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "The Youth Developer's Notebook"- Conducting surveys of youth needs, no date (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Kellogg Project, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Series II. New York State Youth Programs by County
  - Albany County Local Government Interns, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Albany County Local Government Interns Minutes, 1978-1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Albany County Correspondence and Programs, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Albany and Allegheny Counties Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Allegheny County, 1972-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Broome County Legislative Intern Program, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Broome County Government in Action, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Broome County - Miscellaneous, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Broome County - "Toward a Youth Apprenticeship System" Cornell Youth and Work Program, 1993-01 (Box 4, Folder 7A)
  - Broome and Chautauqua Counties Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Cattaraugus County, 1973-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cayuga County, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chautauqua County Legislative H.S. Intern Program, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chautauqua County Wildlife Management and Oral History, 1984-1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chemung County - Local Government Intern Program, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Chemung County - Today's Outdoors Develops America's Youth (TODAY), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Chemung County - Operation Advance, Yesterday and Cohesion Project, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Chenango County (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Clinton County, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Columbia County - Ecology Workshop and 4-H Mobile Home Day Camp Cardboard Carpentry, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Columbia County Teen Parent Partners, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cortland County Legislative High School Internship Program, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cortland County Legislative High School Internship Program, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Cortland County Pilot Youth Community Action Program, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cortland County Youth Court, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Cortland, Genessee, Onondaga, and Schoharie Counties Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Delaware County, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dutchess County, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Erie County, 1973-1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Erie County, Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Essex County, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Franklin County, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Fulton County, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Genesee County, 1973-2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Greene County, 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Hamilton County, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Herkimer County, 1973-1982 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Herkimer County, Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Horseheads- Youth Court (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Jefferson County, 1973-1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Lewis County, 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Madison County Foxfire/Idyllic Foundation, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Madison County, Local Government Intern Program, 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Madison County - Projects not funder, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Madison County, Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Monroe County, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery County, 1972-1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nassau County, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Niagara County Indian Heritage Program, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Niagara County Outdoor Education/Team Naturalist Program, 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Niagara County High School Legislative Intern Program, 1976-1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Niagara County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program, 1978-1984 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - New York City, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Oneida County- Youth Court- Handbook and Correspondence, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Oneida County - A Look at Past, Present and Future, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Oneida County New Directions Project, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Oneida County Past Promises, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Oneida County Local Government Program, 1976-1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Oneida County Pre-Parenting Programs, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Oneida County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Voter Registration Drive, Oneida County, 1987, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Onondaga County Natural Resource Inventory, Miscellaneous, 1975-1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Youth Government Service Program- Onondaga County, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ontario County, 1973-1987 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Orange County, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Orange County Delaware and Hudson Canal Restoration, 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Orleans County, 1973-2001 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Oswego County Little Sandy Creek Resource Study, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Oswego County Salmonid Survey, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Oswego County 4-H Folklore Project, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Oswego County- Miscellaneous, 1973-1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Oswego County Youth Environmental Service, 1976-1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Oswego County- Various Projects, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Oswego County Local Government- 4th Grade Guide, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Oswego County 4th Grade Local Government, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Putnam County, 1976-1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Rensselaer County, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Rockland County, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Rockland County, Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - St. Lawrence County, 1975-1991 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Saratoga County Round Lake Horizons and Folklore, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Local History, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Saratoga County Local Government Program, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Saratoga County They're Off...!, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Saratoga County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Schenectady County, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Schoharie County Local Government Teachers Workshop, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Schoharie County Local Government Teachers Workshop and 4th grade Teachers Manual, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Schoharie County Local Government Teachers Workshop, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Schoharie County Learning About Local Government Through Computers Program, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Schoharie County, 1973-1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Schuyler County Communities in Transition, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Schuyler County 4-H Marsh Education/Wildlife Inventory, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Schuyler County Local History and Folklore (Heirloom), 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Schuyler County Teens and Tots Together/Family Resource Center, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seneca County EFNEP Teen Assistant Program, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Steuben County Local Government Intern/Youth Needs Survey, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Steuben County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Suffolk County Survival Handbook and Miscellaneous, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Suffolk County Local Government Intern Program, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Suffolk County Coastal Projects, 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Suffolk County Coastal Projects (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sullivan County, 1980, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Tioga County Team Vegetable Marketing Program, 1973-1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Tioga County Owego After School Program, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Tioga County Conservation Center, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Tompkins Co. Youth Court, 1960s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Tompkins County Youth Enterprise, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Tompkins County Local Government Intern Program, 1975-1981 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Tompkins County Job Express, Old Mill, Enfield Teen Woman Projects, 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Tompkins County Youth Council, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Tompkins County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Yates County 4-H Bicentennial Park Project, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Yates County Youth Court, Miscellaneous, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Natural Resource Department, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Special Migrant Project- Uninvolved Youth, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Sea Grant Environmental Impact in the Coastal Zone, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Rural Sociology 4-H Leadership Laboratory, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Ulster County, 1977, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Warren County, 1973, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Washington County, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Wayne County, 1975-1984 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Wayne County, 4-H Hispanic Clubs, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Westchester County Natural Resource Inventory, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Wyoming County Intern/Vegetable Marketing/Teens and Parents, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Wyoming County Cornell Cooperative Extension 4-H Government Intern Program (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Local Government Short Course, In-Service Education, 1976-1984 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Series III. Videotapes
  - School to Careers Connecting Youth to the Future, Undated; V-11627 (Box 8)
  - Projects for School and Work: Meeting the Standards, Undated; V-11628 (Box 8)
  - Jobs for the Future: Youth Apprenticeship, Undated; V-11629 (Box 8)
    Presentations from the President's Economic Summit
  - School-To-Work Advisory Program (2 copies), Undated; V-11630-11631 (Box 8)
  - Teacher TV (School to Work), Undated; V-11632 (Box 8)
  - Steve Hamilton conference presentation, Undated; V-11633 (Box 8)
  - 4-H Camp, 1988-09-14; V-11634 (Box 8)
  - ABC News Apprenticeship, 1990-10-17; V-11635 (Box 8)
  - Cornell Youth Apprenticeship, 1993-03-22; V-11635 (Box 8)
  - Symposium, 1991-12-06; V-11636 (Box 8)
  - Youth Apprenticeship featurng Steve Hamilton, 1994-01-20; V-11637 (Box 8)
  - WSKG Directline: Youth Apprenticeship, 1994-01-20; V-11638 (Box 8)
  - School Stories:Better Business, Stronger Schools", 1996-10-20; V-11639 (Box 8)
  - School to Work Advisory Council with Stephen Hamilton, 1996-03-21; V-11640 (Box 8)
    Betacam
  - Projects for School and Work:Meeting the Standards, 1997-07-17; V-11641 (Box 8)